Arthur J. Lumsden Papers
© 2007 University of Connecticut
Arthur J. Lumsden Papers.
undated, circa 1960-circa 1985.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Lumsden, Arthur J.
43 linear feet.
The collection contains documentation of Mr. Lumsden's activities and association with the Greater Hartford Chamber of Commerce, Greater Hartford Corporation, Hartford City Council from the 1960s through the 1980s.
MSS20060243
Biography
Arthur J. Lumsden was born in Lorain, Ohio, and graduated from the Case Institute of Technology (Cleveland, OH). From 1956 to 1981, Lumsden headed the Greater Hartford Chamber of Commerce and was a founder of the Community Renewal Team, an antipoverty agency. After retiring from the chamber, he formed Arthur Lumsden Associates, Inc., which coordinated the financing of private businesses in the Caribbean and Central America through the United States Agency for International Development and Caribbean/Central American Action, Inc. In 1986, he became chairman of Dodd, Mead & Company.
Mr. Lumsden, who resided in West Hartford, CT, and Delray Beach, FL, died of lung cancer on January 3, 1988.
Scope and Content
The collection contains documentation of Mr. Lumsden's activities and association with the Greater Hartford Chamber of Commerce, Greater Hartford Corporation, Hartford City Council from the 1960s through the 1980s. Files identified as "Devco" refer to the Greater Hartford Community Development Corporation which may or not be the same as the Greater Hartford Corporation.
Arrangement
This collection is unprocessed.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to various aspects of Connecticut history. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
Dodd
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Lumsden, Arthur.
Organizations:
Greater Hartford Chamber of Commerce.; Greater Hartford Corporation.; hartford (Conn.)--City Council.
Places:
Hartford (Conn.)
Subjects:
City planning--Connecticut--Hartford.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Publications.; Photographs.; Administrative Records.; Financial Records.; Minutes.; Press releases.; Photocopies.; Notes.; Speeches.
Occupations:
Civi leaders--Connecticut.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by the University of Hartford Library in 2006. Additional materials were received from the donor in January 2007.
Detailed Description
- Inventory, undated, circa 1960-circa 1985
  - Greater Hartford Corporation, Greater Hartford Process, Charter Oak Leadership Medal, Chapel Square (New Haven, CT), Conference on Inflation, Greater Hartford Chamber of Commerce, undated, 1968-1975 (Box 1)
  - Greater Hartford Corporation, Bradley International Airport, Bicentennial Commission, undated, 1967-1980 (Box 2)
  - Greater Hartford Corporation, Hartford City Counil, Bradley International Airport, undated, 1970-1979 (Box 3)
  - Greater Hartford Corporation Board minutes, reports, financials, undated, 1970-1974 (Box 4)
  - Greater Hartford Process, Greater Hartford Corporation, Hartford City Council, Programming, undated, 1970-1976 (Box 5)
  - Devco, Greater Hartford Process, undated, 1970-1980 (Box 6)
  - Tax reform, Health Care, Urban Resouces, Inc., Town & Country Magazine, Urban Coalition of Greater Hartford, undated, 1969-1981 (Box 7)
  - Board of Education, Greater Hartford Chamber of Commerce, Cultural Affairs, Arts Council, Civic Center, undated, 1973-1977 (Box 8)
  - Devco, Greater Hartford Process minutes, Goals for Process, Mission, undated, 1971-1976 (Box 9)
  - Revaluation, Health Center (UConn), Governance, studies, reports, undated, 1965-1977 (Box 10)
  - Greater Hartford Corporation minutes, reports, projects, undated, 1970-1982 (Box 11)
  - Greater Hartford Corporation, undated, 1970-1978 (Box 12)
  - Community renewal, School/University projects, undated, 1964-1975 (Box 13)
  - Bond Issues, Housing, undated, 1968-1975 (Box 14)
  - Coventry, CT, Greater Hartford Corporation, reports, undated, 1968-1975 (Box 15)
  - Coventry, CT, Greater Hartford Corporation, undated, 1973-1977 (Box 16)
  - Civic Center, Charter revision, Board of Education, Citizen's Commission for Effective Government, undated, 1965-1975 (Box 17)
  - NW Hartford Action Program, Greater Hartford Chamber of Commerce, undated (Box 18)
  - Housing Development fund, undated, 1966-1979 (Box 19)
  - Scrapbooks of clippings (2), undated
  - Scrapbooks and clippings, undated (Box 20)
  - Greater Hartford Process, Governor's Conference on Human Rights, Regional Development, Community renewal, 1967-1974 (Box 21)
  - Memorabilia, Conncticut city profiles, White House Conference on Small Businesses, undated, 1973-1979 (Box 22)
  - Connecticut Bar Association, Diaries (calendars), 1958-1962 (Box 23)
  - Devco, Greater Hartford Process, undated (Box 24)
  - Devco, Albany Avenue, 1973-1974 (Box 25)
  - Red Carpet Tour, Economic Development, Town Meeting for Tomorrow, 1971-1979 (Box 26)
  - Housing, Greater Hartford Festival, Social and Recreational Services, Greater Hartford Process, undated (Box 27)
  - Diaries (calendars), University of Hartford dinner, Connecticut Bar Association, 1968-1979 (Box 28)
  - Clippings, Greater Hartford Business Journal, Chamber of Commerce Minutes, undated, 1976 (Box 29)
  - Greater Hartford Arts Festival, Capitol Regional Planning, 1974-1980 (Box 30)
  - Cityplace reports, Hartford Management studies, Hartford City development, Downtown renewal, undated (Box 31)
  - Town Meeting for Tomorrow, Community Development Center, retreats, Artist's Collective, Inc., 1966-1977 (Box 32)